<?xml version="1.0"?>
<PropertyList>


    <!--**********************************************************************

                                          Help


*************************************************************************-->
    <title>Saab AJS-37 Viggen</title>
    <key>
        <name>Backspace</name>
        <desc>Toggle thrust reverser</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>k/j</name>
        <desc>Extend/retract airbrakes (with gear down: keep 'k' pressed to extend)</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-B</name>
        <desc>Toggle airbrakes (with gear down: keep pressed to extend)</desc>
    </key>
	<key>
        <name>u</name>
        <desc>Afterburner on/off</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>q</name>
        <desc>Trigger flare release</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>e</name>
        <desc>Fire selected weapon</desc>
    </key>
	<key>
        <name>[ / ]</name>
        <desc>Radar range decrease / increase</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>J</name>
        <desc>Jettison Drop tank in flight</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Del</name>
        <desc>Yaw damper on/off</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Shift Del</name>
        <desc>Pitch damper on/off</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl Del</name>
        <desc>Roll damper on/off</desc>
    </key>
	<key>
        <name>w</name>
        <desc>Pitch Gearing on/off</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>o</name>
        <desc>Toggle canopy</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>H</name>
        <desc>HUD Brightness</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>h</name>
        <desc>Toggle masterarm</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>I</name>
        <desc>Toggle HUD units. Metric/imperial.</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>c</name>
        <desc>Cycle weapons</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>M</name>
        <desc>Toggle nose wheel steering</desc>
    </key>
	<key>
        <name>Y</name>
        <desc>Landing HUD mode on/off</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-y</name>
        <desc>Ask tower for QFE setting.</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>r</name>
        <desc>Toggle radar</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>f</name>
        <desc>Toggle radar steer order on current selection</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>S</name>
        <desc>Cycle smoke. Off, Yellow or Blue</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>i</name>
        <desc>Toggle HUD to show type or callsign on radar tracks</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>n</name>
        <desc>Cycle next radar track selection</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>N</name>
        <desc>Select radar track center most in HUD</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F</name>
        <desc>Unlock selected radar track</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>E</name>
        <desc>Uncage IR seeker after lock (held: cage/reset seeker)</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl n</name>
        <desc>Target next route-manager waypoint</desc>
    </key>
    <!--<key>
        <name>Ctrl Shift a</name>
        <desc>Continue on current heading, speed and altitude with A/P</desc>
    </key>-->
    <key>
        <name>Q</name>
        <desc>Reset view</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-Shift-q</name>
        <desc>View HUD</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl Left/Right</name>
        <desc>Yaw trim or A/P heading/roll adjust</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-T</name>
        <desc>Select CSS (stability assist) autopilot mode</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-W</name>
        <desc>Select attitude hold</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-A</name>
        <desc>Select altitude hold</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-D</name>
        <desc>Autopilot quick disengage</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-S</name>
        <desc>Toggle autothrottle lever</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-G</name>
        <desc>Autothrottle quick disengage</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Shift PageUp</name>
        <desc>Adjust seat up</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Shift PageDown</name>
        <desc>Adjust seat down</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-E x3</name>
        <desc>Eject</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F5</name>
        <desc>GCI Picture</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F6</name>
        <desc>GCI Dope</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F7</name>
        <desc>GCI Cutoff</desc>
    </key>
    <!--
     <key>
      <name>Shift-backspace</name>
      <desc>Reload A/P</desc>
     </key>
     <key>
      <name>m</name>
      <desc>Toggle configure HUD for final approach</desc>
     </key> -->
    <text><![CDATA[
      Startup
      _______
      Start up engine and systems
      Wait for the engine to spool up and generator to turn on.
      Calibrate the altimeter.
      Apply full throttle with afterburner.
      Release parking brakes.
      
      Takeoff
      _______
      Mind the sidewind indicator in the HUD.
      Pull back on the stick when the distance scale upper marker is aligned with the lower.
      Takeoff at 315 km/h. (170 kt)

      Landing
      _______
      Land with speeds within 220km/h. (119 kt) and an Angle of Attack of 12.0 degrees for standard landing.
      Land with speeds within 195-249km/h. (105-134 kt) and an Angle of Attack of 15.5 degrees and no flare for short landing.
      Deploy reverse thrust and brakes after touchdown.

      Landing with ILS or TILS
      ________________________
      Below the HUD horizon line is a line with a dot in the middle. When within ILS range, align the dot in the center and keep the flight path indicator on it. Close to that same line is also 4 vertical lines, align the top of those to the horizontal line (not the horizon line).
      The heading bug will indicate the touchdown spot.

      Flaps
      _____
      The Viggen control the flaps automatically.
      At takeoff and landing it will set flaps to 30 degrees down.
      In flight it will be set at 4 degrees up.    

      Afterburner stages
      __________________
      The afterburner has 3 stages, the throttle controls this. Throttle position 94% = stage 1, 96% = stage 2, 98% = stage 3
      The nozzle indicator alternate as a afterburner stage indicator.

      Instruments
      ___________
      The angle of attack indicator will act as a pitch indicator when on the ground.
      If the next waypoint is an airport it will be shown as a circle on the radar screen. If a runway is specified it will also show the direction as a line out from the circle.
      The selected radar echo will be shown a '+' on the radar screen.
      Mouse middle clicking on altimeter setting knobs, will reset to standard pressure.

      HUD info
      ________
      The HUD uses Km/h and meters, but this can be switched to imperial with 'I'.
      The HUD switches automatically between takeoff, landing, navigation and tactical mode.
      An exception is when landing mode switch is activated, that will force landing mode, when not in takeoff mode.
      When in takeoff mode the sidewind indicator - -o- - will move to a side according to sidewind.
      The vertical tail on the flight path indicator will move/blink according to AoA and speed in landing mode.
      In tactical mode when the cannon or rockets is selected, a fixed crosshair will appear.
      In tactical mode the reticle change if out of ammo.
      The digital altimeter to the left will use rader (if radar altimeter enabled) below 100 meters (328 ft), a 'R' is shown. when this happens, and show terrain elevation above, up till 9999.
      If the radar-altimeter detects that the altimeter is not calibrated correct, it will blink QFE (happens only below 100 meters (328 ft) above terrain).
      If QFE is displayed, but not blinking, the altimeter have been calibrated correctly.
      The digital airspeed indicator at the bottom, will use Km/h until mach 0.5, after that it will show mach number. If using imperial units, it will show mach number and knots at same time.
      The artificial horizon and pitch lines are spaced 5 degrees.
      To the right is a altimeter scale, below 100 meter the scale will become more detailed and below 50 even more. Above 1000, one floating point decimal precision.
      On the altimeter the symbol '77' indicates where radar altimeter detects the ground to be below plane centerline.
      Next to '0' on the alt scale a '|' symbol will appear if the radar altimeter ground is higher than the altimeter 0.
      The heading at the top is shown as a scale showing 1/10 of heading in degrees. The scale will move to the hozizon line in landing mode.
      Radar tracks are shown as semi-circles, the nearest will also show callsign and distance. In tactical mode the selected radar track is the target, and will be shown as a semi-box, it will change to a diamond with missile lock.
      Nearest tower is shown as a small diamond, with ICAO and distance. It will not be shown in tactical mode though.
      
      Warnings
      ________
      Deploying gear above 30 meters at high and medium speeds will produce a powerful pitch up moment.
      The Swedish Airforce forbids flying in superstall regime, so make sure the control tower do not catch you doing that. :)
      Beware trying to land if the gears are damaged.
      If you try to extend the gears at high speed they won't extend till you get into lower speeds. The limit is 0.65M or 620Km/h (335KTS).
      The gears will not retract on the runway.

      Automatic Thrust reversing
      __________________________
      This will enable the reverse thrust when you touch down with all 3 gears.
      If you take off from a rough strip or without runway, the ground bumpiness will trigger this and prevent you from taking off. So in that case I recommend switching it off.

      Using autopilot to follow target
      ________________________________
      The HUD must turned on and a something selected.
      Press 'f'. Then the auto-pilot will enable automatic thrust, pitch and heading control. The plane will now intercept and closely follow the target.
      If the target changes during the intercept, it will not switch to the new target.
      To stop, press 'F'. Or select another and press 'f' again to follow that instead.

      Using the Selection View
      ________________________
      This view will keep the Viggen in view while at the same time pointing the camera at the selected entity.
      Do not rotate the camera in this view, that will ruin its ability to track the selection. You can however zoom without a problem.

      Repairing
      _________
      In FG 3.2+ you can repair failed systems in the old failure dialogs, but there are many systems that the dialogs does not show. To be sure the aircraft is fully repaired you should select the menu option Repair under the JA37 menu.

      Air-conditioning
      ________________
      When using ALS, the windshield can fog up under certain conditions. Be sure to remember to enable hot air on windshield to be able to see.
      The cockpit windshield and canopy might ice up when using ALS. Be sure to set the aircondition right for removing ice and for pilot comfort.

      Unstable fuel configurations
      ____________________________
      It is entirely possible to fill the fuel tanks in such a way that the plane become too longitudal unstable. I recommend filling up the internal tanks (except the first) evenly to avoid this. Bringing up the performance monitor you can check the static-margin, if below 0.30 meter the plane is dangerous unstable. Most of the time the automatic fuel system will keep the plane stable but under some conditions it can fail to do that, for example with prolonged aerobatic manouvres. Flying level for some time would remedy this in many cases.

      Liveries
      ________
      Livery 59, uses half the texture memory of the other liveries.

      Additional keys
      _______________
      Some additional keys for navigation is listed here:
      
      } - gross freq up
      { - gross freq down
      > - fine freq up
      < - fine freq down
      ) - radial up
      ( - radial down
      * - comm / nav
      & - mhz / khz
      + - volume up
      = - volume down
      Ctrl-. - next waypoint
      Ctrl-, - previous waypoint
      \ - DME

      Trivia
      ______
      400 meter runway is required to takeoff.
      500 meter runway is required to land.
      Service ceiling: 18,300 m (60,000 ft)
      From mach 0.6 till 0.8 it accelerates faster than F-16A. (tested against a Danish F-16A)
      
      Notes:
      _____
      Hangar homepage: https://sites.google.com/site/fghangar
      ]]></text>
</PropertyList>
