<?xml version="1.0"?>
<PropertyList>


    <!--**********************************************************************

                                          Help


*************************************************************************-->
    <title>Saab AJS-37 Viggen</title>
    <key>
        <name>Backspace</name>
        <desc>Toggle thrust reverser</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>k/j</name>
        <desc>Extend/retract airbrakes (with gear down: keep 'k' pressed to extend)</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-B</name>
        <desc>Toggle airbrakes (with gear down: keep pressed to extend)</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>q</name>
        <desc>Trigger flare release</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>e</name>
        <desc>Fire selected weapon</desc>
    </key>
	<key>
        <name>[ / ]</name>
        <desc>Radar range decrease / increase</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>J</name>
        <desc>Jettison Drop tank in flight</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>o</name>
        <desc>Toggle canopy</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>H</name>
        <desc>HUD Brightness</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>h</name>
        <desc>Toggle masterarm</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>I</name>
        <desc>Toggle HUD units. Metric/imperial.</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>c</name>
        <desc>Cycle weapons</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>y</name>
        <desc>Toggle cursor/flight control</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>m/M</name>
        <desc>Main mode selector clockwise/counter-clockwise</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-y</name>
        <desc>Ask tower for QFE setting.</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>r</name>
        <desc>Toggle radar</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>f</name>
        <desc>Toggle radar steer order on current selection</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>S</name>
        <desc>Cycle smoke. Off, Yellow or Blue</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>i</name>
        <desc>Toggle HUD to show type or callsign on radar tracks</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>n</name>
        <desc>Cycle next radar track selection</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>N</name>
        <desc>Select radar track center most in HUD</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F</name>
        <desc>Unlock selected radar track</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>E</name>
        <desc>Uncage IR seeker after lock (held: cage/reset seeker)</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl n</name>
        <desc>Target next route-manager waypoint</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Q</name>
        <desc>Reset view</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-Shift-q</name>
        <desc>View HUD</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl Left/Right</name>
        <desc>Yaw trim or A/P heading/roll adjust</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-T</name>
        <desc>Select CSS (stability assist) autopilot mode</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-W</name>
        <desc>Select attitude hold</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-A</name>
        <desc>Select altitude hold</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-D</name>
        <desc>Autopilot quick disengage</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-S</name>
        <desc>Toggle autothrottle lever</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-G</name>
        <desc>Autothrottle quick disengage</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>R</name>
        <desc>Set target altitude (does not affect autopilot)</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Shift PageUp</name>
        <desc>Adjust seat up</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Shift PageDown</name>
        <desc>Adjust seat down</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-E x3</name>
        <desc>Eject</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F5</name>
        <desc>GCI Picture</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F6</name>
        <desc>GCI Dope</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F7</name>
        <desc>GCI Cutoff</desc>
    </key>
    <!--
     <key>
      <name>Shift-backspace</name>
      <desc>Reload A/P</desc>
     </key>
     <key>
      <name>m</name>
      <desc>Toggle configure HUD for final approach</desc>
     </key> -->
    <text><![CDATA[
      Startup
      _______
      See checklists (Help -> Checklists) for detailled procedures.

      Takeoff
      _______
      Rotation speed is between 250km/h and 300km/h (135 to 160kts).
      Rotate when the upper and lower markers are aligned on the distance scale on the HUD.

      Landing
      _______
      For normal landings, approach is done with an Angle of Attack of up to 12.0 degrees.
      For short landings, approach is done with an Angle of Attack of 15.5 degrees, and no flare.
      Thrust reverser can be engaged on final, and will deploy at touchdown.

      Landing with ILS or TILS
      ________________________
      Below the HUD horizon line is a line with a dot in the middle.
      When within ILS range, align the dot in the center and keep the flight path indicator on it.
      Close to that same line are 4 vertical lines, align the top of those to the horizontal line (not the horizon line).
      The heading bug will indicate the touchdown spot.

      Flaps
      _____
      Flaps (on the canard planes) are tied to the landing gear.
      With gear down, they are deployed 30 degrees down.
      In flight, they are set 4 degrees up.

      Instruments
      ___________
      Clicking on the center of altimeter setting knobs toggles standard pressure (1013.2).
      Viggen is designed to use QFE setting insdead of QNH (calibrate 0m to the airport altitude).

      Displays
      ________
      CI: Center display, radar screen with some navigation information (e.g. waypoint position, as a big circle).

      Modes
      -----
      Operation modes (navigation, landing, tactical...) are selected through
      the main mode selector knob, located on the radar panel, left side, next to the throttle.

      HUD info
      ________
      The HUD uses Km/h and meters, but this can be switched to imperial with 'I'.
      When in takeoff mode the sidewind indicator - -o- - will move to a side according to sidewind.
      The vertical tail on the flight path indicator will move/blink according to AoA and speed in landing mode.
      In tactical mode when the cannon or rockets is selected, a fixed crosshair will appear.
      In tactical mode the reticle change if out of ammo.
      The digital altimeter to the left will use rader (if radar altimeter enabled) below 100 meters (328 ft), a 'R' is shown. when this happens, and show terrain elevation above, up till 9999.
      If the radar-altimeter detects that the altimeter is not calibrated correct, it will blink QFE (happens only below 100 meters (328 ft) above terrain).
      If QFE is displayed, but not blinking, the altimeter have been calibrated correctly.
      The digital airspeed indicator at the bottom, will use Km/h until mach 0.5, after that it will show mach number. If using imperial units, it will show mach number and knots at same time.
      The artificial horizon and pitch lines are spaced 5 degrees.
      To the right is a altimeter scale, below 100 meter the scale will become more detailed and below 50 even more. Above 1000, one floating point decimal precision.
      On the altimeter the symbol '77' indicates where radar altimeter detects the ground to be below plane centerline.
      Next to '0' on the alt scale a '|' symbol will appear if the radar altimeter ground is higher than the altimeter 0.
      The heading at the top is shown as a scale showing 1/10 of heading in degrees. The scale will move to the hozizon line in landing mode.
      Radar tracks are shown as semi-circles, the nearest will also show callsign and distance. In tactical mode the selected radar track is the target, and will be shown as a semi-box, it will change to a diamond with missile lock.
      Nearest tower is shown as a small diamond, with ICAO and distance. It will not be shown in tactical mode though.

      Warnings
      ________
      Deploying gear above 30 meters at high and medium speeds will produce a powerful pitch up moment.
      The Swedish Airforce forbids flying in superstall regime, so make sure the control tower do not catch you doing that. :)
      Beware trying to land if the gears are damaged.
      If you try to extend the gears at high speed they won't extend till you get into lower speeds. The limit is 0.65M or 620Km/h (335KTS).
      The gears will not retract on the runway.

      Repairing
      _________
      In FG 3.2+ you can repair failed systems in the old failure dialogs, but there are many systems that the dialogs does not show. To be sure the aircraft is fully repaired you should select the menu option Repair under the JA37 menu.

      Air-conditioning
      ________________
      Air-conditioning (left side, on a vertical panel) and defogging (right side)
      should be used to avoid fog or ice on the windshield (requires ALS to be visible).
      ]]></text>
</PropertyList>
